HANIF MUHAMMAD KAMIL

- ♥ Sitimulyo, Piyungan, Bantul, Yogyakarta
- **** +628975141800
- https://linkedin.com/in/hanifkamil/
- http://tiny.cc/hanifk-portfolio

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Hard worker with a great passion for Data Science. Have interned in the data field and worked in web development. Encouraged to start independently and learn quickly to advance and improve my skills in Natural Language Processing.

WORK HISTORY

Freelance

Sleman, Indonesia Jan 2023 - Dec 2023

Networking

Sleman, Indonesia Oct 2022 - Jul 2024

Heptaco Digital Media, PT

Bantul, Indonesia Dec 2021 - Mar 2022

Bisa Artifisial Indonesia, PT.

Bandung, Indonesia Nov 2021 - Dec 2021

Dua Empat Tujuh, PT (SOLUSI247)

Yogyakarta, Indonesia Mar 2021 - Sep 2021

Maboor Media Group, PT

Sleman, Indonesia Jan 2021 - Jan 2021

Wordpress Developer

This was a part-time job while I did my copywriting job about business and management.

Professional Development

- Learned Management, Law, and some course of Psychology from books, journals, handbooks, and online course.
- Contributed to Making a book about leadership.
- Created 3 business plan in legal, IT, and finance.

Data Analyst Intern

- Worked on a data processing line to analyze Customer Service performance in 3 companies per month for 2021 & 2022.
- Cleaned very dirty data to take advantage of phone numbers that will be used for promotional needs.
- Analyzed data to classify which customers will receive rewards on the data recorded in 2021.

On the Job Training Data Science

- Created topic model to Identify public opinion about the covid19 vaccine in Indonesia.
- Created NLP recommender system for terrorism cases in Indonesia.
- Created sentiment analysis model to classify Google Play Store reviews from BISA AI application.

Data Scientist Intern

- Created Time Series Model with TensorFlow using Python language from Topic Modeling.
- Created a POS Tagging Project with a team that required reviewing several journals.
- Learned Tableau, Shell Scripting, & MySQL.

IT Staff Trainee

- · Designing multiple Wordpress websites.
- Advertising company products from Instagram and Facebook Ads.
- Editing photos, videos and articles to post on Instagram and Facebook.

QUALIFICATIONS

Udacity

California, United States 2022 - 2022

Universitas Islam Negeri Sunan Kalijaga

Sleman, Indonesia 2014 - 2018

Business Analytics Nanodegree

Courses: Excel Modeling, SQL, and Tableau

Islamic Education

International Journal:

The Enforcement of Counter-Radicalism through Educational Values (Analytical analysis of the Book of I'tiqād by Al-Bukhārī), Journal of Pascasarjana UIN Sunan Gunung Djati Bandung, Vol. 2(3), p. 179-189, Journal indexed in: DOAJ [author: 1].

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python
- Microsoft Excel Modeling
- Text Mining
- Tensorflow
- HTML/CSS

- SQL (MySQL/MariaDB, SQLite & PostgreSQL)
- Tableau
- Machine Learning
- AWS
- UNIX Shell Scripting (BASH)

PERSONAL SKILLS

Communication

Actively expressed opinions when discussing presentations with my team.

Teamwork

Participated in the equipment section at campus events and in the internship.

Critical Thinking

Interpreted new information and made rational decisions after reading several journals to make an article and project.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Received Positive Change Ambassador Badge

2024

This badge is awarded to individuals who successfully complete the Rotterdam School of Management, Erasmus University MOOC 'Driving Business towards the Sustainable Development Goals'.

Received Data Science Bootcamp Certificate

Online training in collaboration with Binar Academy and Digital Talent Scholarship Training Program 2022 by the Ministry of Communication and Information, Republic of Indonesia.

Received Business Intelligence Certificate

Online training in collaboration with Rakamin Academy and Digital Talent Scholarship Training Program 2022 by the Ministry of Communication and Information, Republic of Indonesia.

Received AWS Machine Learning Foundations Course Certificate

2021

Technology Scholarship Program in collaboration with Udacity and Amazon Web Services (AWS).

INTERESTS

- Artificial Intelligence: including Natural Language Processing.
- Networking Events: has participated in various computer, healthcare, Self Development: always eager to learn new skills. and entrepreneurial events.
- Taekwondo: both participation and running small classes.

REFEREES

Referees available on request.